<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Notes from a system engineer&#39;s desk</title>
    <link>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Notes from a system engineer&#39;s desk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 09:53:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Tip - Job re-use within a Stage</title>
      <link>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/004-azdo-tip-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 09:53:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/004-azdo-tip-job/</guid>
      <description>Background Azure DevOps introduced multi-stage yaml pipelines a while ago. It allows us to define our entire Build/Release landscape inside these yaml definitions.
To re-iterate of some terms used in this post:
 A pipeline comprises one or more stages Stage is collection of jobs Job runs on an agent/ agentless Job contains steps (task/script) Steps are the atomic unit to perform a task  Challenge Recently, working our multi-stage yaml pipelines, we hit an interesting behavior with our job template re-use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevOps Tip - Find private APIs</title>
      <link>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/002-azdo-tip-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 15:06:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/002-azdo-tip-api/</guid>
      <description>Problem Often working with Azure DevOps, I hit a wall trying to automate some tasks but there are no REST APIs made public yet.
It was one of those task of automating creation of Environments in multi-stage YAML based pipelines in AzDO.
Quick research reveals that this has been requested in uservoice (please upvote). Let&amp;rsquo;s see one of the very simple ways to discover some of these APIs.
Developers Tools to rescue Using your browser&amp;rsquo;s developers tools you can actually inspect the HTTP requests being made while performing an action in the web portal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#1 Hello World</title>
      <link>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/001-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 12:20:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dexterposh.github.io/posts/001-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>print(&amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;) Write-Host -Object &amp;#34;Hello World&amp;#34; </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>